BERNARDO SANTANA

C (954) 516-9673 • bernardo.santana.dev@gmail.com

SOFTWARE ENGINEER / MOBILE DEVELOPER

Performance Summary

Software Engineer with three years of professional experience. Currently pursuing a Master's degree in Computer Science, with specialization in Computational Perception and Robotics. Looking forward to finding a position as a Machine Learning engineer in any area of research and development. Valuable experience in mobile app development, real-time applications, multithreaded environments and graphics processing.

Technical Skills

- Swift / ObjC
- iOS / Apple TV / Watch kit
- OOP + FRP
- Mobile Apps
- Java / Android

- Machine Learning
- Dynamic Programming
- Tensorflow
- Computer Vision
- Matlab/Octave

- Python
- Django
- RethinkDB
- C/C++
- Multithreading

PROFESSIONAL EXPERIENCE

Gigster October 2016 - present



Freelance Developer

Mobile App development, from UI/UX, Data store configuration, API/REST integration, to more complex features as Animations, Graphics processing and Real-Time communications. Latest projects:

- Marker Your remarkable places. Development and deployment for v2 of the app. Integration with the current API.
- BarStars. Data store modeling in CloudKit. Refactoring and refurbishing of the previous app.
- Nightly.

Bundle UK

March 2015 - June 2016



Software Engineer / Lead Developer

In charge of development and maintenance of the iOS app since the concept phase, as well as the Real-time commenting service for it (python-Tornado). Constant contributions and collaboration with the rest of the app segments: CMS, Machine Learning disambiguation, Design.

- Development and maintenance of the codebase for the native iOS App in Swift, according to the design guidelines
 and meeting the highest standards of quality. Multithreading Techniques (GCD), animations (Core Animation),
 efficient storage (Core Data) and external libraries for networking (Alamofire) and authentication (Facebook API)
 where used.
- Development and maintenance of a commenting server based in Python-Tornado server with a database on rethinkDB to enable Real-Time features in the app.
- Setup features and releases according to the company's goals and milestones.

Artonics International August 2016

Mobile Developer

Redesign and refurbishing of the drawing engine for the mobile app **Nebula** (in the App Store).

- Translation and updating of the deprecated codebase (2010) from Objective-C to Swift
- Redesign drawing methods for speed optimization and responsiveness to leverage Real-time feedback drawing.
- Custom engineering solutions and creation new features.

Mobile Media Networks

September 2014 – March 2015

Software Developer

Development of Mobile Apps in Android, iOS and web based (Phonegapp/Cordova) platforms. Gained valuable experience modifying, fixing, adding features and creating numerous apps.

Projects:

- Played an active role in the new-product development from concept through launch phase for **Dualvis.io**, a
 multi-platform general TV experience enhancer app for iOS. Runner-up startup project in Startup-Chile
 contest. Mocked-up, developed and tested the complete interface.
- Updated and maintained the code base for **Meridiano Extra** in both Android and iOS. Increased responsiveness, added other sport features, fixed serious memory leaks and refreshed the interface.
- Gained mobile development skills by fixing bugs, adding new features and running tests in the following apps: **My Renault** (Colombia), **Diario La República** (Colombia), **Chevrolet** (Colombia)

General Electric June 2013 - July 2014

Intern

Design and documentation of an Auxiliary Fluid Handling System for a Central Processing Facility in the Orinoco Oil Belt. Gained extensive experience in GE-IP control software for industrial equipment, utilizing GE-Proficy and Fanuc products.

Academic thesis: Automation System proposal for a Central Processing Facilities in the Orinoco Oil Belt

EDUCATION AND TRAINING

M.S Computer Science, Computational Perception and Robotics

GEORGIA INSTITUTE OF TECHNOLOGY.

2017-2019

2008-2014

B.S. Electronics Engineering. Cum Laude

SIMON BOLIVAR UNIVERSITY, VENEZUELA

Selected Courses: Robotics - Control Theory - Signals & Systems - Electronic Devices - Solid State Electronics - Mobile Communications, Optical Communications - Telecommunication Systems - Computer Architecture - Programming

Robotics / Telecommunications Semester

CZECH TECHNICAL UNIVERSITY AT PRAGUE, CZECH REPUBLIC

Personal and Extracurricular Activities

Machine Learning, Deep Learning, R programming MOOCs (Coursera) Participation in numerous Hackathons Attended Capital Factory Accelerator at Austin, TX Member of AIESEC - Exchange participant in England. Certification CCNA Level 1 (Cisco)